Highly focused, goal-driven and dedicated worker with a passion for Data Analytics. Proven ability to work individually and in groups, meet deadlines, learn quickly, and utilize exceptional analytical skills to provide quality research and information. Strong ability with leading groups and delegating tasks and responsibilities to complete goals and achieve success.

Software skills:

- Tableau
- R
- Python
- MongoDB
- Excel

- Pandas
- Matplotlib
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- MySQL

Education

University of California, Berkeley Extension

Certificate in Data Analytics

June 2018 – Present

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data and Machine Learning.

University of California, Merced

Bachelors of Science in Chemistry

August 2013 - May 2017

Experience

Laboratory Technician

CW Analytical - Oakland, CA

March 2017 – June 2017

Supported senior chemists by performing elaborate extractions procedures on a variety of products for further analytical testing. Collaborated with other laboratory technicians to troubleshoot, resolve problems, and help with special projects.

- Monitored products quality to ensure compliance to standards and specifications.
- Maintained, repaired, set up, and calibrated complex instrumentation and equipment.
- Conducted tests to assist senior staff in making qualitative and quantitative decisions.

HPLC Analyst

June 2017 – January 2018

Anresco Laboratories - San Francisco, CA

Performed several analytical testing methods to ensure samples meet FDA requirements and regulations. Operated and maintained different modular and compact HPLC systems.

- Responsible for performing data entry and generating reports.
- Designed experiments to troubleshoot equipment issues.
- Demonstrated ability to improve upon current laboratory practices through ability to learn new skills, procedures, and processes.

Process Technician

January 2018 – Present

C3 Nano Inc. – Hayward, CA

Worked in a start-up company responsible for designing, synthesizing, and fabricating high-performance conductive platforms based on the unique properties of nanomaterials.

- Maintained process batch records while performing various steps of nanomaterial production.
- Documented and maintained records and notebooks in a neat, thorough, and accurate manner.
- Successfully interpreted Data using R to draw conclusions and optimize performance.